praisecharts.com 2019-05-18

# Privacy Policy | PraiseCharts

In the simplest terms, it is our desire to protect your information and only use it as necessary for your ease and benefit as you interact with us.  We have provided you with some a short summary of what that looks like, along with the longer version that provides all the specifics and details.  As always, if you have questions, please [contact us](https://www.praisecharts.com/contact-us/).

For your protection, all personal information that we gather from your account is safely stored on our secure server. PraiseCharts does not sell or lend its contact list to any other business. All personal information gathered is volunteered, and non-personal information is gathered through web analytics tools -- each for the purpose of serving you more effectively and efficiently.

We do not collect credit card information. All financial transactions are handled through authorized, third-party merchant providers -- namely, PayPal and Converge/Elavon.

Privacy Policy 

1\. GENERAL  
At PraiseCharts (Sonreign Media, Inc., DBA PraiseCharts Publishing, Inc.), we are committed to protecting your privacy.  
For this reason, we collect and use personal information only as it might be needed for us to deliver to you our products, services, and support.

This Privacy Policy explains: 

• What Information we collect and why we collect it;  
• How we use that Information; and,  
• To whom we disclose it; 

It also describes options we provide for you to access, update or otherwise take control of your personal information that we process. 

If at any time you have questions about our practices or any of your rights described below, you may reach our Data and Technology Team by contacting us at support@praisecharts.com

At PraiseCharts we provide you with various services including an online store, arranging and transcribing services, administration of copyrights and facilities to contact customer support ("Services"). PraiseCharts also provides you with products that are listed on the online store, including but not limited to charts, sheet music, audio files, as well as subscription and membership services (“Products”). 

2\. WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?  
We collect information so that we can provide the best possible experience when you utilize our Services and/or buy our Products. Much of what you likely consider personal information (name, address, phone number, email address, other identifying information) is collected directly from you when you: 

(1) create an account or purchase any of our Products (such as name, email address, password, organization name billing information, phone number);  
(2) log-in with Facebook (such as name, email address, Facebook ID);  
(3) log-in with email (such as email address and password); or  
(4) request newsletters or other information from us (such as email address).

However, we also collect additional information when delivering our Products and Services to you to ensure necessary and optimal performance. These methods of collection may not be as obvious to you, so we wanted to highlight and explain below a bit more about what these might be and how they work: 

Account related information is collected in association with your use of our Services, such as account information, purchases of Products, information requests, customer service requests and notes or details explaining what you asked for and how we responded.

Cookies and similar technologies on the Site allow us to track your browsing behavior, links clicked, Products purchased, your device type, and to collect various information, including analytics, about how you use and interact with our Products and Services. This allows us to provide you with more relevant product offerings, a better experience on our Site, and to collect, analyze and improve the performance of our Products and Services. We may also use your location so that we can give you access to country specific services. For additional information, and to learn how to manage the technologies we utilize, you can read our Cookie policy in Section 5 below. 

Information about Usage of Services is automatically collected when you use and interact with our Services, including metainformation, log files, cookie/device IDs and location information. This information includes specific information about your interactions with the features, content and links (including those of third-parties, such as social media plugins) contained within the Services, Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type and settings, the date and time the Services were used, information about browser configuration and plugins, language preferences and cookie information, information about devices accessing the Services, including type of device, what operating system is used, device settings, application IDs, unique device identifiers and error information , and some of this information collected might be capable of and be used to approximate your location.

3\. HOW DO WE USE COLLECTED INFORMATION?  
The information we collect is limited in its use and purpose to only that (1) for which we have been given permission, (2) as necessary to deliver and allow you to interact with the Products and Services you purchased, (3) respond to your requests or to manage your accounts or (4) as we might be required or permitted for legal compliance or other lawful purposes. These uses include:

3.1 Delivering, improving, updating and enhancing the Products and Services we provide to you. We collect various information relating to your Product purchase and use, and/or interactions with our Services. We utilize this information to:

• Improve and optimize the operation and performance of our Services   
• Diagnose problems with and identify any security risks, errors, or needed enhancements to the Services  
• Detect and prevent fraud and abuse of our Products and Services and systems  
• Collect aggregate statistics about use of the Products and Services  
• Understand and analyze how you use our Products and Services; and what Products and Services are most relevant to you.

Often, much of the information collected is aggregated (or statistical data) to understand how individuals use our Products and Services, and is not linked to any personal information, but to the extent it is itself personal information, or is linked or linkable to personal information, we treat it accordingly.

3.2 Sharing with trusted third parties. We may share your personal information with third parties with which we have partnered to allow you to integrate their services into our own Products and Services, and with trusted third party service providers as necessary for them to perform services on our behalf, such as:

• Processing credit card payments  
• Serving advertisements  
• Conducting contests or surveys  
• Performing analysis of our Services   
• Communicating with you, such as by way of email or push notification messages sent on mobile.   
• Customer relationship management  
• Offering extended services through API connections to other sites 

We only share your personal information as necessary for any third party to provide the services as requested or as needed on our behalf. These third parties are subject to strict data processing terms and conditions and are prohibited from utilizing, sharing or retaining your personal information for any other purpose than as they have been specifically contracted for (or without your consent).

3.3 Communicating with you. We may contact you directly or through a third party service provider regarding Products or Services you have signed up for or purchased from us, such as necessary to deliver transactional or service related communications. We may also contact you with offers for additional services we think you’ll find valuable if you give us consent, or where allowed, based upon legitimate interests. You don’t need to provide consent as a condition to purchase our Products or Services. These contacts may include:

• Email  
• Text (SMS) messages  
• Push Notifications  
You may also update your subscription preferences with respect to receiving communications from us by contacting us directly on support@praisecharts.com.

3.4 Transfer of personal information abroad. If you utilize our Services from a country other than the country where our servers are located, your communications with us may result in transferring your personal information across international borders. Also, when you call us, we may provide you with support from one of our locations outside your country of origin. In these cases, your personal information is handled according to this Privacy Policy.

3.5 Compliance with legal, regulatory and law enforcement requests. We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process, to protect our property and rights or the property and rights of a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we consider to be illegal or unethical.

To the extent we are legally permitted to do so, we will take reasonable steps to notify you in the event that we are required to provide your personal information to third parties as part of legal process. 

3.6 Website analytics. We use multiple web analytics tools provided by service partners such as Facebook Analytics, Google Analytics, MOZ, Optimziely, Hotjar, etc to collect information about how you interact with our Site, Products and Services, including what pages you visit, how much time you spend on each page, and IP information. We use the information provided by these tools to improve our Services. These tools place persistent cookies in your browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit our Site. Each cookie cannot be used by anyone other than the specific service provider (ex: Facebook for Facebook Analytics). The information collected from the cookie may be transmitted to and stored by these service partners on servers in a country other than the country in which you reside. These services use technologies to collect data on our users’ behavior and their devices (in particular device's IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). They then store this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Though information collected does not include personal information such as name, address, billing information, etc., the information collected is used and shared by these service providers in accordance with their individual privacy policies. You can control the technologies we use by managing your settings through Privacy Settings or the ‘cookie banners” that may be presented when you first visit our webpages, or by utilizing settings in your browser or third-party tools, such as “Disconnect” and others. As well, you can opt-out to the creation of a Hotjar user profile, Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar’s use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this opt-out link.

We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this section.

3.7 Targeted advertisements. Targeted ads or interest-based offers may be presented to you based on your activities on our Site and based on the Products you purchased. These offers will display as varying product banners presented to you while browsing. Our third party partners may use technologies such as cookies to gather information such activities in order to provide you with advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests, and to measure advertising effectiveness.

10.0'DO NOT TRACK' NOTIFICATIONS  
Some browsers allow you to automatically notify websites you visit not to track you using a “Do Not Track” signal. There is no consensus among industry participants as to what “Do Not Track” means in this context. Like many websites and online services, we currently do not alter our practices when we receive a “Do Not Track” signal from a visitor’s browser. To find out more about “Do Not Track,” you may wish to visit www.allaboutdnt.com.
